chapter-18:
    qa1:
        context: 'When the gov-ernment decided to spend huge sums to help the American colonists against Brit-ain, the budget went into total crisis.With France on the verge of financial col-lapse, Louis XVI was forced to call a meet-ing of the Estates-General, repre sentatives of all three estates meeting together, to raise new taxes. The Estates-General had not met since 1614  because French kings were so powerful.'
        question: 'Who called a meeting of the Estates-General in 1789?'
        answer: 'Louis XVI'
    qa2:
        context: 'The new Constitution of 1791 set up a limited monarchy. There was still a king, but a Legislative Assembly would make the laws. The new body was designed to be conservative. First, only the so-called “active” citizens—men over 25 who paid a certain amount of taxes—could vote. All others were considered “passive”  citizens with equal rights but no vote. Second, the method of choosing its 745 deputies meant that only relatively wealthy people would serve. Not only the clergy, but also govern-ment officials and judges, would be elected. Local governments were put in charge of taxation. The influence of the new govern-ment began to spread throughout France.'
        question: 'The Constitution of 1791 set up which form of government?'
        answer: 'limited monarchy'
    qa3:
        context: 'Napoleon then turned to his Continental System to defeat Britain. The aim of the Continental System was to stop British goods from reaching the European conti-nent to be sold there. By weakening Britain economically, Napoleon would destroy its ability to wage war. The Continental System also failed. Allied states resented being told by Napo-leon that they could not trade with the British.'
        question: 'What was the goal of the Continental System?'
        answer: 'stop British goods'
    qa4:
        context: 'Napoleon raised another French army of devoted veterans who rallied from all over France. He then readied an attack on the allied troops stationed across the border in Belgium.At Waterloo in Belgium on June 18, 1815, Napoleon met a combined British and Prussian army under the Duke of Wellington and suffered a bloody defeat. This time, the victorious allies exiled him to St. Helena, a small island in the south Atlantic. Napoleon remained in exile until his death in 1821, but his memory haunted French political life for many decades.'
        question: 'Where was Napoleon defeated for the fi nal time?'
        answer: 'Waterloo in Belgium'
chapter-19:
    qa1:
        context: 'The cotton industry became even more productive when the steam engine was improved in the 1760s by James Watt, a Scottish engineer. In 1782, Watt made changes that enabled the engine to drive machinery. Steam power could now be used to spin and weave cotton. Before long, cotton mills using steam engines were found all over Britain. Because steam engines were fired by coal, not powered by water, they did not need to be located near rivers.'
        question: 'Which engineer improved the steam engine so it could drive machinery?'
        answer: 'James Watt'
    qa2:
        context: 'The country became a single massive market for the manufactured goods of the Northeast.Labor for the growing number of facto-ries in the Northeast came chiefly from the farm population. Women and girls made up a large majority of the workers in large textile (cotton and wool) factories.Factory owners sometimes sought entire families, including children, to work in their factories.'
        question: 'From where did labor for the factories in the United States mostly come?'
        answer: 'farm populations'
    qa3:
        context: 'European cities and towns dramatically grew. Industrialization spurred this growth. By 1850, British and Belgian cities were home to many industries. With the steam engine, factory owners could locate their plants in cities. People moved from the country to the cities to find work.In 1800, Great Britain had one major city, London, with a population of about 1 mil-lion.'
        question: 'In what did industrialization trigger dramatic growth?'
        answer: 'cities and towns'
    qa4:
        context: 'The haughty Austrian foreign minister, Prince Klemens von Metternich (MEH•tuhr•nihk), was the most influential leader at that meeting in Vienna. Metternich claimed that the principle of legitimacy guided him. He meant that lawful monarchs from the royal families who had ruled before Napoleon would be restored to their positions of power. This, they believed, would ensure peace and stability in Europe. The victorious powers had already restored the Bourbon king to the French throne in 1814.'
        question: 'Who was the most influential leader at the Congress of Vienna meeting in 1814?'
        answer: 'Klemens von Metternich'
    qa5:
        context: 'In the same year, 1830, three more revo-lutions occurred. Nationalism was the chief force in all three of them. Belgium, which had been annexed to the former Dutch Republic in 1815, rebelled and cre-ated an independent state. In Poland and Italy, which were both ruled by foreign powers, efforts to break free were less suc-cessful. Russians crushed the Polish attempt to establish an independent Polish nation. Meanwhile Austrian troops marched south and put down revolts in a number of Italian states.'
        question: 'What ideology or ideologies were behind the 1830 revolutions?'
        answer: 'Nationalism'
    qa6:
        context: ' When the Prus-sian legislature refused to levy new taxes for the proposed military changes, William I appointed a new prime minister, Count Otto von Bismarck. Bismarck has often been seen as the fore-most nineteenth-century practitioner of realpolitik—the “politics of reality,” or politics based on practical matters rather than on theory or ethics. Bismarck openly voiced his strong dislike of anyone who opposed him.'
        question: 'Who was the politician who practiced realpolitik?'
        answer: 'Otto von Bismarck'
    qa7:
        context: 'Czar Alexander II decided to make some reforms. Serfdom, the largest problem in czarist Russia, was not just a humanitarian issue, but a complicated one that affected the economic, social, and political future of Russia. On March 3, 1861, Alexander issued an emancipation edict, which freed the serfs. Peasants could now own property and marry as they chose. The government provided land for the peasants by buying it from the landlords'
        question: 'What was the largest problem in czarist Russia?'
        answer: 'Serfdom'
    qa8:
        context: 'For the true romantic, poetry was the ideal art form. The romantics viewed poetry as the direct expression of the soul. Romantic poetry gave expression to one of the most important characteristics of romanticism—its love of nature. Roman-tics believed that nature served as a mirror into which humans could look to learn about themselves. This is especially evident in the poetry of William Wordsworth, the foremost English romantic poet of nature.'
        question: 'What did romantics view as the direct expression of the soul?'
        answer: 'poetry'
    qa9:
        context: 'In biology, the Frenchman Louis Pasteurproposed the germ theory of disease, which was crucial to the development of modern scientific medical practices. In chemistry, the Russian Dmitry Mendeleyev in the 1860s classified all the material ele-ments then known on the basis of their atomic weights. In Great Britain, Michael Faraday put together a primitive generator that laid the foundation for the use of elec-tric current'
        question: 'Who classified all the material elements known in the 1860s based on their atomic weights?'
        answer: 'Dmitry Mendeleyev'
